• CV.pdf

Michael Garifullin - Technical Lead

Co. Kildare, Ireland, Work Permit in Ireland: Stamp 4 (no work permit required), <u>+353 85 2209967</u>, <u>garifullin@gmail.com</u>

ABOUT ME

I'm fluent with modern web development process

I particularly enjoy working on my projects when I can offer to business fastest and best ways to achieve business goals.

I'm a big fan of cutting corners when it's appropriate, I also like to offer unconventional solutions and find out-of-the-box solutions.

DB optimisation and resolving complicated productions issues is a very usual thing for me.

A special pleasure for me is writing a postmortems as a result of solving non-trivial problems in order to share the gained experience with colleagues, it helps me to structure the gained knowledge once again and to analyse how similar situations can be avoided in the future.

Using front-end frameworks as VueJs and React doesn't cause me any problems but my main focus is backend and infra for my web projects. For me, programming language and frameworks are just a tools to achieve business goals, so if I feel it's necessary, I'd rather use Python or Go Lang as more appropriate technologies if it will make the solution faster and more reliable but my favourite technology for solving issues is still PHP.

Rich experience of testing code in functional and unit way on a different levels including e2e regression tests in hybrid service ecosystems.

Good understanding of services architecture in a modern way (async, queues, microservices). Obviously it's amazing to plan solutions that will be reliable, extensible and easy to maintain for long term.

I believe that Clean Code is not just an idea but the way to achieve fault-tolerant and bulletproof solutions. And that's what I try to convey to my developers. I love sharing knowledge, for me it is a way to strengthen my capabilities, because when you are not only you, but also a team focused on the result, then the achieved goals become bigger.

In mentoring it is important for me not only to deliver knowledge, but I am also well aware that it takes much more effort to maintain and assimilate this knowledge in practice, but the result is worth it. I like to review code and discuss opportunities for improvements with colleagues. CI/CD is not just a modern approach to me, but a way to reduce time to market for business features

I am a person who can blend seamlessly in with others. Open-minded to the new technologies.

EXPERIENCE

Technical Leader, Smartbox Group, Dublin, Ireland, *since December 2017 (5 years and 7 months)* I'm part of the team which is responsible for a booking service (smartbox.com/fr). I'm responsible for resolving cross teams integrations. Presented few concepts for improving our technological stack. Brought new tooling in the project (static analysis and snapshot API testing). Worked on the roadmap of modernization for the project **Achievements:** CI/CD migration from jenkis to gitlab. Integration of Email Marketing Platform. Led the development of new tasks that generate new business value. A lot of improvements for Agile-framework used in team.

Senior Backend Developer, OpenSoft Technologies, Saratov, Russia, *Jan 2014 – Dec 2017 (4 years)* Worked on improving online typography service overnightprints.com. Cross teams interactions. Full stack feature oriented development.

Achievements: Integrations for new payment systems. Integration with warehouse suppliers. Developed a system for improved delivery tracking.

Full-stack Developer, Freelance, remote, *May* 2012 – *Jan* 2014 (1 *year and* 9 *months*) Integration with payment gateways. Development of REST/SOAP services. Supervision in terms of feature delivery.

Project Manager, Mute-lab, Saratov, Russia, Oct 2011 - May 2012 (8 months)

Conflict management. Resolving integration issues with payment gateways. Providing service to enterprise clients, such as Coral TRAVEL, Aviacassa.ru, Aviakassa.ru, Travel.ru

Project Manager, Websynergy, Saratov, Russia, Jul 2010 – Oct 2011 (1 year 4 months)

Managing customers expectations. Assisting foreign customers (fastautosales.com). Implementation of projects for corporate customers – Unimilk, Beeline.

Head of IT department, Unima, Saratov, Russia, May 2008 – Jul 2010 (2 years 3 months)

Management of the development processes at all stages of production for a small web design studio.

Head of IT department, Pronto Samara, Saratov, Russia, *Jul 2005 – May 2008 (2 years 11 months)* Maintaining infrastructure (50+ workstations and 5 servers). Database services. Support FreeBSD servers. Accountant services on Windows 2003 Server DBMS MS SQL.

Software Developer, Narva Consulting LLC, remote, *Aug 2004 – May 2005 (10 months)*

Refactoring a corporate site. Development tools intra-corporate information exchange between remote agents.

EDUCATION

Saratov Chernyshevsky State University, Saratov

Sep 2001 – May 2007 Applied Mathematics and Computer Science

Extras

- **Cultural Experiences**: I really enjoy the time to research new technologies which might be useful for a project. I think that the lessons learned during my daily duties helps me a lot with understanding how to growth my kids as worthy people.
- **Social Impact**: I love to participate in the life of the local community and assist with organisation of cleaning out days of our area.
- Personal Interests: A huge fan of jogging, bicyclist.

© 2023